Goodness.
真是的
Snooping through HQ's confidential data?
竟敢擅自查看总部的机密数据
What were you thinking?
你到底在想什么
I know, I'm a disgrace.
哎呀 真是不好意思
This is about Prosecutor Hosorogi's case, isn't it?
是细吕木监察官的案子吧
Quit getting so involved over someone who's dead anymore.
你不要再为了逝者而勉强自己了
But… this is…
这…可是…
I'm telling you to keep your eyes on the future.
我的意思是让你往前看
You've got to move on for those who are gone too.
连同逝者的份一起努力
About your daughter…
您女儿的事…
I'm sorry.
对不起
Listen… Iwanome.
我说…岩野目
I'm living my life.
我会活下去的
For my daughter's sake, not just my own.
这也是为了我的女儿
And I intend to fulfill my duties until my dying breath.
我一定会把自己的使命贯彻始终的
(Dead Mount, Death Play)
(《尸体如山的死亡游戏》)
(Episode 18: The Revenge) You're really something, Inspector Habaki.
(#18 The Revenge-复仇-) 您真了不起啊 幅木警官
What happened to living for your daughter?
您之前说您是为了女儿
Did you even mean any of it?
那些话难道都是假话吗
Daughter?
女儿
Of course, I mean it.
怎么会是假话呢
Hey, hey.
喂喂
You think that after I went so far as to sacrifice my daughter to get here,
我用女儿才换来的地位
I'd just give it up?
我怎么可能会轻易放手呢
You gotta be kidding me!
不是吧 喂
Calm down, leader.
请你冷静点 系长
This is still better than Lemmings, right?
与旅鼠军团相比 他已经很好对付了
You've got a point there.
你说得也是
Are you okay, Mr. Iwa?
你没事吧 岩先生
Yatsu!
八津
I started to get suspicious when I passed a group of officers acting odd…
刚才我遇到了一些奇怪的警察 我觉得他们很可疑
I scraped together everyone from Comps-3.
所以就召集了三辑的人
We're not interrupting anything, are we?
没给你添麻烦吧
Nice move, but I'll thank you later!
做得好 我晚点再跟你道谢
Huh?
哇
Whoa, whoa.
哎呀哎呀
Inspector Habaki?
幅…幅木警视正
So, leader, what's he being charged with?
那么系长 他犯了什么罪
Glad you're so quick on the uptake.
你们能理解情况真是帮大忙了
It's about Mr. Hosorogi.
是细吕木先生的事件
Maybe I should thank Fire-breathing Bug?
我是不是该感谢一下赴火之虫呢
Thanks to you. I made it in time.
多亏他们 我终于赶上了
A phone call?
电话吗
To whom? That "Higuro" guy?
是打给谁 是冰黑那个家伙吗
Or someone else…?
还是说是别人…
-Arase! -Got it!
-荒濑 -收到
That's it! Keep that up-
好 就这样
A gun?
手枪吗
This is the headquarters.
这里可是总部耶
Why can he carry a gun? Who is he aiming at?
他为什么能持枪 目标是谁
Get out of there, Pops!
快躲开 大叔
-Good work. -Yes, sir.
-辛苦你了 -是
We'll meet again on the other side of the sky.
我们在天空的彼端再会吧
I know that guy!
我记得那家伙是…
Darn it!
可恶
No way, hey!
不是吧 喂
What are you doing-
你打算做什么
Don't!
住手
What the hell is going on, Mr. Iwa?
这…这到底是怎么回事啊 岩先生
Yatsu, you and pops go after Inspector Habaki!
大叔和八津 你们去追幅木警视正
Hey.
喂
These guys are still…
这些家伙还…
I guess this is the end of the road.
到此为止…了吗
I don't wish to…
我们…本不想殃及…
burn the righteous.
正义…之人
Wait, where am I?
咦 这里是哪啊
-Hey! Why am I being arrested? -This is…
-等等 为什么把我抓起来啊 -这是…
Ouch!
好痛
This feels familiar.
这种感觉真是似曾相识
I heard about this before,
虽然之前我就听说过这件事了
but… So this is what it's all about, huh?
没想到 原来是这么一回事吗
You figured something out, didn't you?
你发现什么了吗
The Fire-breathing Bug must be one person, and yet not one person.
赴火之虫是一个人但又并非一个人
Something just outside the realm of common sense.
他们是稍微超出常识范围的
A hypnotist, perhaps?
催眠师…吗
We should split up and search.
我们兵分两路去找吧
Roger that.
收到
Darn it. Kochou is gonna scold me later.
可恶 之后胡蝶又要念我了
This has to be the place.
应该是这里吧
Yo, Habaki.
喂 幅木
Oh! Oh!
哦哦…
I can't believe it's really you.
没想到您真的来了
When did you get to japan?
您是什么时候来日本的
I just got in today.
我今天才刚到
Anyway, while I was looking for a hotel.
我正打算找间饭店来住
I heard that HQ got an emergency call from you.
然后就听说你紧急联络了总部的事
Thank you for that power outage.
哦哦…非常感谢您制造了那场停电
You're too good to me.
真是让您为我费心了
You don't have to thank me.
你不必道谢
You've done good work so far.
毕竟你至今为止都很努力
I expect you to keep it up.
而且今后也会继续努力吧
Speaking of good work,
对了
you've managed to bring all sorts of goodies to the organization.
你一直以来都为组织奉献了不少呢
At the lab where they carry out the experiments, but they're really only slaughtering people.
为了那个以实验为名 而虐杀无辜的实验室
You even presented your own daughter to them as a test subject.
你甚至还把亲生女儿送上了实验台
You're really Habaki.
真不愧是你
Thank you for the kind words.
多谢您的夸奖
I'm sure my daughter is rejoicing from beyond the grave.
想必我的女儿在九泉之下 也会感到高兴的吧
Habaki.
幅木
You're mistaken on two counts.
你误会了两件事
What?
什么
When I said "You've done good work so far.
"你至今为止都很努力"
And I expect you to keep it up",
"…而且今后也会继续努力"
I wasn't talking about you.
这句话并不是指你
What?
您的意思是…
Didn't I tell you?
我不是说了吗
There's no need to thank me.
你不必道谢
I've been wanting to abandon you for a long time.
因为我早就想抛弃你了
And your second mistake-
然后是第二件事
"From beyond the grave"
九泉之下
is an expression used only for the dead, isn't it?
这个词是用在死人身上的
It's been a while, Shitty Dad.
好久不见了呢 我该死的父亲
N-No…It can't be.
难…难道
You're Soara, aren't you?
你是…索亚拉吗
That's right.
没错
She is Habaki Soara.
她就是幅木索亚拉
The daughter you gave over to a product of Sabaramond.
她就是被你献给塞巴拉隆多的产物的 那个女儿
Or more accurately,
不 正确来说
the illegitimate child you don't know how to deal with, so you tossed her.
是你不知道该如何处置的私生女
You never even tried to get to know her, so we never told you.
我看你也没兴趣知道 所以之前就一直没告诉你
Your daughter being the first case to survive the experiments.
你的女儿成为实验的第一例幸存者了
Congratulations to you.
恭喜你
Her codename is Arahabaki.
她的代号是亚拉幅木
She ranks higher even than you now.
她现在的地位已经在你之上了
She's asked me for a special favor.
她拜托了我一件事
She personally wants to execute the father who treated her like a guinea pig.
那就是她想亲手杀掉 那位把她当成小白鼠的父亲
I've thought about you all this time, Father.
我一直都很想念你呢 父亲大人
W-Wait.
等 等等
I'll pay back all the pain I've suffered.
我会把我受到的所有伤害 全都还给你的
Darn it!
可恶
Aww, what a touching father-daughter reunion.
父女的重逢真是令人感动呢
Ah, Lulu.
嗨 露露
Ahh!
啊啊啊啊啊
What's wrong, Father?
怎么了 父亲大人
This is only the tip of the iceberg…
这才刚开始呢
Compared with the pain I've endured for the past decade.
这种程度哪里能比得上 我这十年所受到的痛苦
I've
我啊
made up my mind.
早就决定好了
Even just once would've been fine.
哪怕只有一次
If you had come to check on me after the fact…
只要你有来确认我的情况
Then I'd spare your life.
我就会饶你一命
Lucky for me. You're a cold-hearted bastard.
你能如此无情 真是太好了
That's our target for today.
我们今天的目标好像就是那个
Him?
是吗
I-I can still make it up to you.
我 我还是有利用价值的
I'll find you the sorcerer who came from the other side of the sky.
我马上就能帮组织找到 来自天空彼端的魔法师
There's no way you could do that.
哎呀 凭你是找不到的吧
Please just give me a chance!
请再给我一次机会吧
I think you've made it pretty far by only looking ahead.
虽然你之前一直积极地向前看
But really, you should've spared at least a glance behind you.
但你也应该稍微回顾一下过去了
Like when it comes to Soara.
包括索亚拉的事
What?
什么
Or this very moment.
也包括现在这个瞬间
What do--
什么意…
Huh?
啥
Was that a hit?
咦 打中了吗
Clean headshot.
精准命中
We can ignore the girl with him.
和他在一起的人好像可以不用管
Still…
可是
I can't believe she wanted to test the skills of the Horojima siblings.
说什么想试一下幌岛姐弟的本事
We are only allowed to snipe that battered old geezer.
却只让我们射杀那个被打的大叔
Revenge from the Shinjuku intermediary agency is really boring.
新宿中介屋的复仇真是有够无聊
I'm off here.
我要出发了
Could you get things ready?
麻烦你做一下准备
Yes.
是
Boss, give me an order.
老大 给我指示
Okay.
好
You've got three minutes, Arahabaki.
我给你三分钟 亚拉幅木
Sicut vis (As you wish).
sicut vis(你自便吧)
This is bad.
不好
What is it?
咦 怎么了
Let's pull out of here.
我们赶快撤退吧
Or at least lay low on the middle floor.
或是在中间的楼层躲一下
Too late.
来不及了
Huh?
什么
She's coming right for us.
对方直接来了
Hey.
嗨
It's you guys, isn't it? You peeping toms.
是你们干的吧 偷窥者们
It's an emergency situation.
完蛋了
It seems like we're going to die.
看来 我们要死了
Not yet.
还没呢
I was only able to hurt him half as much as I wanted to.
我才只出了一半的气呢
You took my life's revenge from me,
你们夺走了我人生中复仇的机会
so you're gonna make it up to me, got it?
你们会赔偿我的吧
Were you aiming for my eye? Good one.
哈 你瞄准是我的眼球吗 好啊
Go.
去吧
Tch.
啧
So there's a whole family of you peeping toms.
偷窥狂还挺多的嘛
They're from…
你是那时候的…
Are we being watched?
我们该不会被监视了吧
Is this for all the backstabbing and running away and stuff?
他们是负责处理变故的人吗
Clarissa isn't so foolish she'd leave rookies on their own.
克拉丽莎可没天真到 会放任新人为所欲为
I really don't like her.
唔 那个女人真的很讨厌
You…
你这家伙
But we also got saved.
不过我们也得救了
Thank you…
谢谢…了
So cute.
好可爱
Oh, you're really cute.
喂 你好可爱啊
Hmph, don't think I'll forgive you just because you're cute.
哼 你可别以为你很可爱 就能让我原谅你
I've got a cutie in my gang too.
因为我的同伴里也有个可爱的家伙
Huh?
嗯 咦
Where'd they go?
老大他们去哪了
Huh? Has it already been three minutes?
什么 难道三分钟已经过了吗
Oh, no way! Darn it.
哇 不是吧 可恶
Miss Clarissa.
克拉丽莎小姐
I apologize for dropping by so late.
这么晚打扰你真是抱歉
There's somebody I desperately want to find.
我无论如何都想向你打听一个人
I need your help.
我需要你的帮助
L-Lisa?
丽…丽莎
This is my first time meeting you.
我和你是初次见面 对吧
You're Sayo Shinoyama?
你是四乃山小夜吗
Yes, you know me?
是的 你知道我吗
I only know that you are Polka's family.
我只知道你是波尔卡的家人
Ah, Miss Clarissa.
啊 克拉丽莎小姐
Sis Sayo and Mr. Rozan know about Corpse God, just them, though.
只有小夜姐和吕算先生 知道尸神殿的事
I see.
是吗
Well, you're free to tell them as much as you like,
要不要告诉别人是你的自由
but just be careful.
不过你要多加小心
You're the son of the wealthy Shinoyama.
你毕竟是大财阀四乃山家的公子
If whoever was targeting Polka Shinoyama found out,
要是被盯上四乃山波尔卡的人知道了
it'd lead to all sorts of trouble.
说不定会招来麻烦的
What is it?
怎么了
The intermediary agency has contacted Polka Shinoyama and your younger sister.
中介屋去见四乃山波尔卡 和主人的妹妹了
Remain on standby for now.
你先暂时待命
if you notice anything unusual, you can take action directly.
如果察觉到事情不对 你就直接行动吧
Yes, sir.
遵命
Lisa Kuraki.
仓木丽莎
She really is a pain in the neck.
她真是个棘手的人
I will be careful.
我会小心的
Then it should be okay if we speak here.
那么 我直接在这里说也没关系了吧
Polka.
波尔卡
Or, Corpse God.
不 尸神殿
I have a job to ask of you.
我想委托你一件工作
Can you come with me?
你可以跟我一起来吗
Sure, but…
可以倒是可以
I think something's happened to Takumi and the others.
匠他们好像也遇到了什么事
It is not a good idea to leave Sis Sayo alone.
让小夜姐一个人留下不太好
Ah, don't worry about this.
这你不用担心
The young lady of the Shinoyama is still at home.
四乃山家的大小姐还留在家里
Please protect her well until my associate gets back.
在我的人回来之前请好好保护她
Hmph, wily fox.
哼 女狐狸
The police office has been invaded by Solitaire.
警局被雪天鸦入侵
Officers who were not in their right minds went on a rampage.
还有神智不清的人引发暴动
A gun was fired at an inspector before the suspect turned it on himself.
警察对自己人开枪后用手枪自杀
Someone tampered with the power system.
电力系统被动了手脚
And during the blackout, both Solitaire and Habaki got away.
雪天鸦和幅木都在停电时逃跑了
Our territory has been intruded on far too much in too many ways for one single day.
今天光是在一天之内 我们的地盘就被闹了个鸡犬不宁
Superintendent General, did you suspect Inspector Habaki from the start?
话说 总监阁下您一开始 就在怀疑幅木警视正吗
I hadn't narrowed it down to him for sure.
我并没有锁定他
But I've known for a while now
不过很早之前
that there was a traitor among upper management.
我就知道干部里有内奸了
Five years ago,
五年前
I was one step away from finally tracking them down.
我们差一点就能把他逼出来了
The one who was closest to cracking it disappeared along with the evidence.
然而最接近真相的人 却和证据一起消失了
Could it be…
您说得难道是…
You see anything?
你能看到什么吗
Yes, it's someone who's recently died.
嗯 我能看到刚死不久的人
I can make it so only those of us here can see him.
我可以让身边的人看到他们
Please do it.
拜托你了
You've grown into a fine man.
你变得挺有男子气概的嘛
You're Inspector Habaki, right?
你是幅木警视正吧
It's taken me a while,
虽然花了我不少时间
but with this latest incident, I've finally found you.
不过我终于通过这次的事件找到你了
Habaki.
幅木
Y-Y-You. I remember you. I remember you.
你…你这家伙 我记得你 我记得你
Y-Y-You're the one who made H-Hosorogi's
处理掉细…细吕木… 那家伙的尸…尸体的
corpse-e-e d-d-disappear.
就是你吧…
Yes, I'm terribly sorry about that.
是的 请节哀顺变
I killed him after a long and tumultuous affair.
我与他发生男女之间的纠葛 于是我就把他杀了
Or at least, that's what you'd wanted it to look like.
你想让事情变成这样 对吧
Habaki.
幅木
He was on the short list of suspects…
虽然他在嫌疑人的名单里没错
But now he's dead?
可他却已经死了
Was he killed by Lisa's man?
是丽莎派人杀的吗
But why in a place like this?
可是为什么会选择这个地方呢
Ohhh! Ahhh!
啊啊啊啊啊啊
I can't believe you would make mincemeat of your lover's corpse without any hesitation, you deviant.
你这个恶人 竟然毫不犹豫地 就把恋人的遗体变成了肉酱
Getting rid of you, for me, is the highest compliment.
只要能摆脱你 这对我来说就是最好的赞美
I only have one question for you.
我只想问你一件事
Who's the one who issued the order to have Mr. Hosorogi killed?
是谁下令让你杀害细吕木先生的
Y-Y-You think I'd t-t-tell?
你觉得我会说吗…吗…
-Polka. -Already on it.
-波尔卡 -我已经在做了
Ohh! I'll tell you as a souvenir from the netherworld.
对 对了 作为奔赴黄泉的礼物 我告诉你一件事吧
What did you do?
你做了什么
It's a spell to induce a compliant state of mind.
我用了诱导精神的术式
Although it's far from brainwashing,
虽然远不及洗脑术
I've tipped the scales heavily in favor of his abundant ego.
但我让他心中自傲的天秤大幅倾斜了
Yes.
是啊
I have sacrificed so much.
我一直都在奉献 一直都在奉献
To the products of Sabaramond.
为了那些塞巴拉隆多的产物
You know Mr. Sabaramond?
你知道塞巴拉隆多先生吗
Ohh… That power…
噢…噢…你的力量
Could it be that you're… you're…
难 难道你就是 你就是
the sorcerer from the other side of the sky?
来自天空彼端的魔法师吗
Are you looking for me?
你在找我吗
Ohhh! Now that great man will accept me.
噢…这样一来我就能得到 那位大人的认可
And I'll show my foolish daughter as well.
也能让我那愚蠢的女儿 知道我的厉害了
Daughter?
女儿
Yes, yes.
是啊 是啊
I have given everything to them!
啊啊 我把一切都献给了那些大人
Even my own daughter!
就连我的女儿也是
She should be grateful!
她应该心怀感激
Because she could die for the organization and me!
因为她能为组织和我而死
But instead she seeks revenge on me!
可是她却要向我复仇
What?
什么
Habaki's memories are running through my head?
我脑海中浮现出了幅木的记忆…
You're going to a dreamland.
你要去如梦一般的地方了
You should be thankful.
你应该心怀感激
Under the influence of Polka, I…
在波尔卡的影响下 我也…
Polka?
波尔卡
-Can you lend me some money? -These are fragments mixed in with Habaki's memories.
-稍微借我点钱吧 -这些混杂在幅木的记忆中的片段
-You're a big shot in the empire now. -Are these Polka's-
-你现在不是帝国的大人物吗 -这是波尔卡的…不
No. Corpse God's memories?
是尸神殿的记忆吗
Didn't you make a fortune from the last war?
你不是在之前的战争 赚了不少吗 是吧
After all, you have to feed your mom and little sisters.
毕竟你得养活你的老妈和妹妹们嘛
Right?
是吧
N-Now, don't be mean.
别 别那么无情嘛 我说
You would not starve them, even if you do not care about me, right?
先不说我了 你也不愿意让他们饿死吧 对吧
Heh-heh, sorry.
嘿 嘿嘿 抱歉
These fellas from Nyanild
只要杀了你
said they'd give me more drugs
努安伊路德王国的那些家伙
if I killed you.
就会给我更多的药 他们已经答应我了
So if you're going to hold a grudge against anyone, blame those guys.
你要恨就去恨王国的那些家伙吧
Well, there's actually no need to hold grudges.
不对 其实根本就没必要怨恨
Not just you,
不只是你
my wife and your little brothers and sisters…
我老婆 你的弟弟还有妹妹
They're all…
全都那个
They were sold for a decent price.
卖了不少钱呢
The whole family's been of use to me to the very end.
你们一家人都派上了用场
You should thank me.
你应该感谢我才对
Huh? Huh?
啊 啊
This is…
这是…
Miss Clarissa.
克拉丽莎小姐
I'm still very calm now.
我现在还很冷静
I should draw even more information from that man.
得从那个人身上获取更多的情报才行
I know this,
我知道这一点
but,
但是
may I do as I please?
我可以随心所欲地处置他吗
Wha-Wha-What are you going to do?
哇啊啊啊 你 你要做什么
You're the only one who can perform the duties of the grim reaper in this world.
这个世界只有你才能当死神
Corpse God.
尸神殿
Do as you wish.
你自便吧
How does it feel, my dear friend?
怎么样 我的挚友
For a necromancer like you to be made into one of the undead.
身为死灵术士的你 成为死灵族的感觉如何
It was a curse designed to destroy the body
这是能够破坏肉体
in order to prevent it from reviving.
并防止死灵复活的神器
I expect it was prepared by
能够准备这种东西的人
a corrupt holy woman from the Geldwood Church.
也只有盖尔德伍德教团里 那烂到骨子里的圣女了吧
A technique to destroy the soul was also applied, but…
虽然被施加了破坏灵魂的术式
I know
可我伊斯莉丝
I did not raise your soul to be so weak and frail.
并不记得有把你的灵魂 培养得那么脆弱
Do not forget
不要忘了
that it was only on a whim that I revived you as an undead this one time.
你已经在我的心血来潮下 变成了死灵族
Huh? Is my memory playing tricks on me?
哎呀 是我记错了吗
"How fortunate I was able to make his brain into his soul core before it was destroyed."
"能在脑髓被破坏之前 确保灵魂之核平安无事真是太好了"
I remember you saying that with a huge sigh of relief.
你之前说完后不是还松了口气吗
Your memory deceives you.
你记错了
You sure?
你确定吗
Then am I also misremembering when you pleaded with Utsurojuza?
那么你之前故意向虚铳座低头的事 也是我记错了吗
THIRD-RANKING IMPERIAL COURT SORCERER OF THE BYANDY EMPIRE, Didn't you let him take back the poison
(巴亚蒂帝国宫廷魔魔术师 第三席 虚铳座) 你不是让他把侵蚀脑髓的毒
UTSUROJUZA and curse that were about to eat away at his brain?
和诅咒都收起来了吗
Your memory is completely mistaken, Your Majesty.
陛下 你完全记错了
I think a medicine man ought to examine you.
你应该让疗病术士给你看个病才对
Especially the head.
特别是脑袋
You're just the worst, you beautiful old witch.
嘴巴真毒 这个美魔女老太婆
Hahaha.
哈哈哈
Only you dare to call me, the emperor, crazy.
也只有你敢说我这个皇帝的脑子坏了
Not only do you have no comforting words for your apprentice,
你不仅没为自己的弟子着想
but then you call His Majesty crazy?
甚至还说皇帝的脑子坏了 真是太恶劣了
You agree with me, right?
你说是不是
Corpse God.
尸神殿
Alright, alright. Utsurojuza.
好了好了 虚铳座
Let it be.
就这样吧
I'm not crazy,
我的脑子虽然没坏
but it's true that my head's unstable and coming to a boil.
但我倒是真的非常不安和焦急
My friend.
挚友
It's all because you were assassinated, okay?
这都是因为你被刺死了哦
Hmm? What's the matter?
嗯 你怎么了
It takes some effort to make bones speak.
让骨头开口说话还需要一番功夫
However, I understand what he is trying to say.
不过 我知道他想说什么
It's because you still treat him as before,
因为你还是像以前一样对待他
so he is confused, Your Majesty.
所以他有些困惑 陛下
He feared you would cut off all relations after seeing him as undead.
他害怕你会因为他变成了死灵族 而跟他绝交
Oh?
是吗
Evidently underestimated.
那你还真是看太轻了
I didn't mean me.
啊 我说的不是你看轻我哦
I meant you.
而是你把自己给看轻了
And don't go thinking about getting revenge on your dad.
还有 你不要再去想 要向你父亲复仇的事了
There's no need for you to sully yourself with that lowlife.
你不必为了这种小人物而玷污了自己
Don't forget, my friend.
别忘了哦 挚友
No matter what becomes of you,
无论你变成什么样
I and the empire itself will always be on your side.
我和这个帝国永远都是你的伙伴
Rizdilusia Redrazalf.
利兹迪鲁夏·雷托拉沙鲁夫
Ahhhh!
呜啊啊啊啊啊
God don't play games.
神不会戏弄生命
I believe that even now.
我现在仍然相信这一点
Playing around with people's lives because of emotions
凭藉内心的感情玩弄生命的人
makes you as immature as me.
都是像我这样的半吊子
How many times do I have to tell you?
你要让我说多少遍
There's no need for you to sully yourself with this lowlife.
你不必为了这种小人物而玷污了自己
I don't remember summoning you here…
我不记得我有叫您过来
Your Majesty.
陛下
(Episode 19: The Friends)
(#19 The Friends-亲友-)